The incredible attack on Pearl Harbor.
Tora! Tora! Tora! is a war, history, drama film directed by Toshio Masuda.
In the summer of 1941, the United States and Japan seem on the brink of war
after constant embargos and failed diplomacy come to no end.
Tora!", named after the code words used by the lead Japanese pilot to indicate they had surprised the Americans,
covers the days leading up to the attack on Pearl Harbor, which plunged America into the Second World War.
Admiral Husband E. Kimmel, played by Martin Balsam.
Admiral Isoroku Yamamoto, played by So Yamamura.
General Walter C. Short, played by Jason Robards.
Henry L. Stimson, played by Joseph Cotten.
Commander Minoru Genda, played by Tatsuya Mihashi.
Colonel Rufus S. Bratton, played by E.G. Marshall.
(Japanese: トラ・トラ・トラ！) is a 1970 epic war film that dramatizes the events leading up to the
Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor in 1941, from both American and Japanese positions.
The film was produced by Elmo Williams and directed by Richard
Fleischer, Toshio Masuda and Kinji Fukasaku.
It features an ensemble cast, including Martin
Balsam, Joseph Cotten, So Yamamura, E.G.
Marshall, James Whitmore, Tatsuya Mihashi, Takahiro
Tamura, Wesley Addy, and Jason Robards.
It was Masuda and Fukasaku's first English-language film,
and first international co-production.
The tora of the title, although literally meaning "tiger", is actually an abbreviation of a two-syllable codeword (i.e.,
totsugeki raigeki 突撃雷撃, "lightning attack"), used to indicate that complete surprise had been achieved.
The film was released in the United States by 20th Century-Fox on September
23, 1970, and in Japan by the Toei Company on September 25.
It received mixed reviews from American critics, but was praised for its historical
accuracy and attention to detail, its visual effects, and its action sequences.
was nominated for five Oscars at the 43rd Academy Awards, including Best
Cinematography and Best Film Editing, winning Best Visual Effects (L.B.
Abbott and A.D.
The National Board of Review ranked it in its Top Ten Films of 1971.
A 1994 survey at the USS Arizona Memorial determined that for Americans the film was the
most common source of popular knowledge about the Pearl Harbor attack.
The film explores themes of japan, hawaii, world
war ii, pearl harbor, u.s. navy.
The tone is emotional.